let's play the chaos game in a pentagon
first start with a DOT anywhere inside
the Pentagon then we're going to iterate
a procedure where at any given stage we
move
0.618 of the distance between the
current dot and a randomly chosen vertex
on the Pentagon think of rolling an
imaginary five-sided die and then moving
towards the corresponding vertex what
happens when we iterate this process
30,000 times in this picture we've
shaded the dots corresponding to the
vertex to which we move at any given
stage after 30,000 iterations if we
throw away the first few iterations we
see that the limiting shape will always
look like this diagram no matter where
we started this is an amazing fractal
generated from a simple process note
that the number 0.618 is special it's
approximately one over the golden ratio